<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>HNDR.ME</title><link href="http://hndr.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://hndr.me/feeds/journals.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://hndr.me/</id><updated>2014-10-06T12:55:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Me, an Average Programmer</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/me-an-average-programmer" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-06T12:55:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2014-10-06:blog/me-an-average-programmer</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am a professional programmer, but, unlike a lot of programmers appear to be, I didn’t spend my childhood coding a game on a Commodore or writing a program for Apple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt;. In fact, even though I have always been a geek, I wasn’t really interested in programming until much, much&amp;nbsp;later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember the time when my parents bought me and my brother a computer. I was in the fifth grade, and my brother was in the 7th. My uncle just opened a computer shop and my brother’s school curriculum now includes an hour of computer lesson every week (a push to improve computer literacy, I guess). So, to support my uncle’s new venture and so that me and my brother can learn more about computer, my parents purchased one for us even though they didn’t know how to use it or have any interest in learning it. I still remember that during the time, for some reason, people have this belief of if you know how to use a computer, you wouldn’t have a problem securing a job, that the computer is the future. I think this was around 2001. Now that I know more about the industry and its history, I wonder if the tech bubble had something to do with it. I didn’t care though. I only thought about playing games on&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computer was an Pentium machine ( I don’t remember which one, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;III&lt;/span&gt; ) running Windows 98. I still remember playing around the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt; and discovering a cool feature every now and then. One of the things I loved to play was the desktop theme. When I found out that I can change the colour scheme, icons, and sound effects, I was so fascinated by it that I switched the theme several times every time I turned the computer on. The computer came with a number of software pre-installed, including a few video games. My uncle taught me and my brother how to start some of the games, and with it, he also gave us an instruction not to click anything that is labelled “Uninstall” since that will break the computer. Of course, we clicked it anyway. Of course, that removes a bunch of stuff from the computer, and we were whining that the computer broke, because the game can’t be started. So, we called by uncle, and he installed the game again, and of course, a few days after that, we uninstalled it again. I don’t even know why were we so obsessed with the “Uninstall”. Believe it or not, even though it was 2001 and the dot-com bubble has come and went, consumer internet didn’t really exist in my hometown until several years later. So, without internet, for me and by brother, that box in front of us was everything we knew about computer. Every now and then, my uncle came and installed some new games for us, and we would play that game all the time till we got&amp;nbsp;bored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being your average nerd, I sucked at sports. I was bored by school. I played bunch of computer games. I loved Anime and Manga . When I got into high school, instead of going to a conventional high school, I applied for a vocational school. Not because I have an idea on what I wanted to do, it was mostly because it was pretty close to my house, and my brother and a lot of my relatives went to the same school as well. At the time I applied, the school has just started a new program, called Computer Networking. Since the other majors (Accounting, Hospitality, Office Administration, etc) didn’t interest me at all, I chose to major in Computer Networking, not because I enjoyed the subjects. I didn’t even know what kind of stuff I would get to learn by choosing that major. The only reason I chose the major was because I know that I wouldn’t enjoy the other options, also, I naively thought that we are going to spend a bunch of time playing around with&amp;nbsp;computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the years, I played a bunch of video games, and I was pretty good at most of them. I enjoyed the challenge. I always try to finish all the game that I picked up, sometimes even when I didn’t really enjoy the game. Around the time I got into high school, consumer internet has started to spread around. Even though I didn’t have internet connection at home, there are cyber cafes pretty much everywhere and they are pretty affordable. So, being a gamer that I am, I frequented a bunch of gaming forums and message board ( I probably would have downloaded a bunch of them too if it weren’t for the download speed that were way too slow). Got access to a bunch of information, strategies, and&amp;nbsp;cheats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe cheating in games played a significant role in putting me in the path that got me to be a programmer. As many gamers probably can understand, certain games can get seriously tedious to play, and at that point, most probably would resort to cheating. At first, I only played around with cheat code and exploits that I got to know from information on the internet, then I got to know about Game Trainers, and, after a while, the cheat and hacks I found on the internet just doesn’t cut it anymore. Sometimes I don’t want to have 9.999.999.999 Gold and immortality. I wanted more control. Eventually, I found something else that I enjoyed in trying to cheat in games. I loved the thrill of bending the rules of the games, sometimes even more than the game&amp;nbsp;itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, I used simple tools such as Cheat Engine to modify memory values, and then I eventually dropped to a debugger to change how the game behave, and with it, I learned a little bit of assembly language to help me understand how the game work. I also got into playing MMORPGs, and being the cheapskate that I am, I refused to pay for in-game items. I tried to cheat in the game as well. None of techniques that I had learned hacking single-player games worked. I was stumped. Then I learned how multiplayer games stores the game data on the server, and attempting to change the game data on my computer is only going my account banned. Of course, being the cheapskate that refused to pay for in-game item while at the same time being a lazy ass that refused to spend hours grinding, I looked for other ways to get what I want. Initially, I simply wrote a simple automation using AutoIt that simulates key strokes and mouse clicks. It worked pretty well, but with this approach, I had to keep the game window active and couldn’t do anything else the computer, and since I played the game from a cyber cafe, I can’t exactly just leave the place to do something place either. After some searching, I learned about packet monitoring tools like Wireshark, with it, I can simulate game activity and run the bot even without starting the game client. Later, as I got even more greedy, I tried to look into more advanced things like how to run the bot on multiple accounts at the same time, make the bot harder to detect, make it smarter and die less often, and so on. I realised I had to learn some programming. So I googled around for some programming tutorials, and so I downloaded the DevC++ and tried to learn some&amp;nbsp;C++.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time I learned about looping and conditional in C++, I got distracted again. This time by Computer Graphics. I am sure many gamers are inspired by the graphics in the games they played and wondered how they can create something like it. Some of my favourite games are the Final Fantasy Series, and as many fans would know the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CG&lt;/span&gt; in those games are simply amazing. So, I set out to find out how to create these CGs as well. I downloaded a bunch of software packages to learn how to create these art. I played around with Photoshop, 3ds Max, Maya, Zbrush, and a bunch of other things as well. While I was learning how to use Photoshop, I got into photo-manipulation as well. None of this actually got anywhere though, while I learned a bit on how to use these software packages, my artistic ability are still in the dump.  While I was still messing around with 3D modelling and other visual arts, I graduated from high school. Like many people my age, I was confused on what I wanted to do. I was very fortunate to get a scholarship offer from a government program, but I didn’t know if furthering my education is what I wanted, or if it is the right choice for&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I got the scholarship offer, I never even thought about going to a university to study. At the time, I had been working part-time as a computer technician for quite a while, and I was going to go full-time at the job until i figured out what I wanted to do. Well, I ended up taking the scholarship offer, majored in Computer Science, got set on a track to a career in tech, and became a programmer. Well, actually, its not that straightforward. I majored in Computer Network and Security, and for the first few years, I don’t have any interest in software engineering. But then again, that will be a story for another&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So well, that’s it. I know, after such a long-winded article, its kind of anti-climactic to end my story this way, and I’m pretty sure its a pretty boring story too. But, that is my story. I was not some kind of computer whiz who wrote a computer program at the age of six. I wasn’t even seriously interested in programming until my second year of university. To this day I am still not sure where my life is going. There are many things that I wanted to do, but I don’t know how to get there. I am not some kind of celebrity programmer. I haven’t produced anything of significant value. I am still learning new things everyday. I am a pretty average programmer, and I am okay with&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Recent Distractions</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/recent-distractions" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-13T22:53:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2014-09-13:blog/recent-distractions</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Its a Saturday night, and I have nothing else to do. Hence, this&amp;nbsp;post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I am distracted by these&amp;nbsp;days:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side Projects,&amp;nbsp;Travelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data processing and analysis, data mining, data&amp;nbsp;visualisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bootstrapped business, recurring revenue,&amp;nbsp;marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DDD&lt;/span&gt;, automated tests, software design&amp;nbsp;patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s about it. I don&amp;#8217;t know what will come out of it, or what will end up distracting me from&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Random Updates</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/random-updates" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-01T20:44:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2014-06-01:blog/random-updates</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Starting from this month, I have been officially in my current job for 6 months, which also means I just got out of the probation period for the company. During the past 6 months, I have been doing a bunch of various things, and also learned a lot of stuffs that I have never really thought&amp;nbsp;about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the main reason I am writing this post right now is simple: I am procrastinating. I have several conference videos that I wanted to watch, and also several libraries and frameworks that I want to try out, but for some reason, my mind keeps drifting away. This week, three developers I work with left the company, one of which is the person who mentored me during my internship with them. I have known about the departure a few weeks prior, and I didn&amp;#8217;t actually thought about it much, but it turns out, the departure of these colleagues does affect me quite a bit. I thought I am used to changes, but it seems like I&amp;#8217;m not. It made me think about stuffs. Stuffs that are hard to put in writing, stuffs that are uncomfortable to think&amp;nbsp;about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, most of my work now revolves around the back end, I had to learn a bunch of stuffs on server administration, distributed architecture, and I also ended up using the Laravel &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt; framework a lot. Which is actually very fun and exciting, until something blows up and data are lost, that is. Anyway, all that stuffs that I learned during the period makes for a lot of materials that I wanted to write up, but for various reasons (mainly me being lazy), I never ended up getting to it. While using the static site generator is excellent in terms of simplicity, it also meant that I have to open up my text editor and generate a new site even just to post a short draft. I considered migrating my site to &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/"&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;, but having to manage a server pushed me sticking with Pelican. What I do now is to write my drafts in Evernote, and then paste them here when it is ready, which isn&amp;#8217;t exactly a seamless process considering Evernote&amp;#8217;s lacking support for Markdown. That being said, I do hope it would help me to write&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2014 - Thoughts</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/2014-thoughts" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-29T14:33:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2014-01-29:blog/2014-thoughts</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s rather late for a new year posting, considering we are almost entering the second month 2014 by now, but well, what can I say, I haven&amp;#8217;t got much time to write the past few months, and now I am only writing because I&amp;#8217;m stuck waiting for the next ferry back to my hometown that isn&amp;#8217;t coming for 2&amp;nbsp;hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 is pretty special for myself. New years are usually a chance to start something for most people, a fresh start, where any unpleasant things that has happened happened &amp;#8220;last year&amp;#8221;. That said, for most people, these words are simply figurative speech. While the calendar has indeed changed, most people&amp;#8217;s live didn&amp;#8217;t, and life still goes on as usual. I myself have never really celebrated new year as anything other than a chance to get together with friends and do some catching&amp;nbsp;up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 is different. Quite a lot has changed in my life in the past few months. I recently graduated from university, with that, I also started a new job as a software&amp;nbsp;engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s pretty much it. And wow, it&amp;#8217;s sounds pretty trivial now that I think about it. But still, a new year usually calls us to reflect about past events. I have been thinking about what kind of person I&amp;#8217;ve been, what kind of person I want to be, what I want to do in my life, pretty much my life direction in&amp;nbsp;general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back about myself, there are many things that I wish I&amp;#8217;d done differently. Especially during my university years. I was too much of a coward to take more risk in pretty much everything. People who I didn&amp;#8217;t take the chance to know more about, trips to places I didn&amp;#8217;t travel to, skills I didn&amp;#8217;t spend more time learning, and many others. I wasted too much time doing things that I didn&amp;#8217;t really care about just because they are things I&amp;#8217;m comfortable&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t want to sound too arrogant, but I was one of those guys who didn&amp;#8217;t study much, yet still managed to get high scores in class. I honestly didn&amp;#8217;t find the works for my bachelor degree to be too difficult, and I find as long as I pay attention during classes, the only time I would need to study outside of classes would be a day or two before an exam. Because of this I ended up with a lot of free time. But I stupidly spent all these free time doing things like watching movies, surfing the web aimlessly, and other time wasting activities in general. I regretted not using those free times that I had to socialize more, join a student organization or two, learn how to play one or two instruments, and so on. I used to see my friends who seemed to barely have any free time and think what is it about this cozy university life that takes up so much of his time. Well, the answer is simply he made the most of his time in university. I used to think that university life is way too easy and boring. Well, how can it be not easy and boring, I did it&amp;nbsp;wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I am no longer a student, I am consciously trying to be more active and socialize more. It&amp;#8217;s not easy though, I am your average geek and an through and though introvert, and meeting new people isn&amp;#8217;t my forte, but I am trying, and hopefully this will help me find what I want to do in&amp;nbsp;life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I would like to change is my health. I have been obese as far as I can remember, and now that I have a full time job as a programmer, I can&amp;#8217;t think of any reason that would somehow magically change. I need to start taking responsibility of my health, and not make excuses for me failing to lose weight. I am going to buy a bicycle when I get back from my leave (yes, typical. Always start someday in the future. Seriously though, I&amp;#8217;ll stick to this plan), and I&amp;#8217;ll start commuting to work with my bike. Hopefully this would push me to exercise&amp;nbsp;more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In work, while I do love what I do, and the work environment is awesome, it&amp;#8217;s not all rainbow and unicorns either. In my first project, I had to work with an existing system that well, let&amp;#8217;s just say it&amp;#8217;s difficult to work with. I myself also committed a big mistake in another project, I chosen a technology stack that no one else seemed to be interested in learning. I personally do love and believe in this stack (and I do think that the way we have been programming needs some serious improvement), which is why I chose it, but I came to learn that in a collaboration project I need to consider more than just the technical merit. I need to consider the people I&amp;#8217;ll be working with, and how comfortable they are in learning these things. The project ended up behind schedule, mostly because other in my team aren&amp;#8217;t comfortable with the new (not that new though) technology yet, and me being too much of an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OCD&lt;/span&gt;, spent way too much time than I should have cleaning up codes that other people just wrote. Lesson learned. Shipping should comes first before technical aesthetic. Save the beautiful code (not that I am really capable of writing code that good anyway :P) for personal&amp;nbsp;projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, when I was applying for jobs several months ago, I had several offers that comes with higher salary than the one that I accepted (my current job). The reason I took on this job is because I felt that I can learn the most about tech with this environment, and since this is my first job anyway, I didn&amp;#8217;t really think of looking for a position with the highest salary so that I can stay for years earning more money. The opportunity to learn. That was what I thought I should be looking for in my first job. But now, I am worried that I maybe forming a bubble around myself to get comfortable and not challenging myself. So that&amp;#8217;s another thing that I should work&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In life, well, I am still looking for what I want to do in life, but well, for starter, I would love to be able to travel more, get to know more people, hopefully I am able to find people dear to me. While I am an introvert, I do have several close friends that I value very much, but to be honest, the people that really matters to me are my family. For some reason I feel like it&amp;#8217;s not supposed to be this way, and I should have more people that I care about. I don&amp;#8217;t know, I guess this is just one of those things that I would know when the time&amp;nbsp;comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On traveling, well, I have been wanting to travel for several years, but for the past few years, as a poor student living on a scholarship, it&amp;#8217;s not really financially feasible. Not to mention the traveling cost, event the some of visa application fee would&amp;#8217;ve cost me a month&amp;#8217;s living cost. Now that I am working and earning a salary, I hope to be able to save up some money and travel somewhere. Even though visiting the old European cities have been on my mind for quite a while now, I don&amp;#8217;t really have a place that I want to visit yet. It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter where, I am still looking for a place that would pull me&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the life goal, well, I thought about it a lot, but I still can&amp;#8217;t find an answer that I am satisfied with. I guess this is just one those things that you can&amp;#8217;t rush. Well, there is no need to rush it anyway. Some people spend their whole life looking for a destination without finding one, maybe there isn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that&amp;#8217;s goes for my 2014 reflection. I don&amp;#8217;t really want to make another new year&amp;#8217;s resolution as my 2012 and 2013 resolution aren&amp;#8217;t completely crossed out yet, so here is my 2014 &amp;#8220;goal&amp;nbsp;guidelines&amp;#8221;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise more, start commuting to work with the bike, lose at least&amp;nbsp;15KGs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be more active, socialize more, don&amp;#8217;t get trapped in the comfort&amp;nbsp;zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a new project, stick to it, and make it something that&amp;nbsp;counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop taking life so seriously. It&amp;#8217;s just&amp;nbsp;life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it, I guess. Ah, of course, I didn&amp;#8217;t really include any geek topic so far, so I guess I should mention some. Well, I plan to do another re-design for this site, make new Pelican theme. Let&amp;#8217;s see how that goes. I also plan to rewrite the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hdra/WP_Mog"&gt;Mog WordPress theme&lt;/a&gt;, clean up the codes, and maybe build it on top of one of the popular &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; framework so that it&amp;#8217;s more&amp;nbsp;maintainable.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>New Stage in Life</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/new-stage-in-life" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-16T19:47:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2013-11-16:blog/new-stage-in-life</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a while since I posted anything. The last time I posted something was in August, so it has been around two months. Since then, many things have&amp;nbsp;changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my last day in college on July. I had my convocation ceremony on October, so yep. I am officially holding a B.Sc. degree. It was pretty exciting. Also, now I am working as a Software Engineer! I am now officially a professional programmer. I write code for a living. I also just moved to a new place today, so things has been very hectic in the past few months. From the job search, tying things up with my scholarship, looking for a place to rent, starting a new job, all these things has been taking up most of my&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last project I worked on was the WordPress theme that I uploaded on &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/themes/mog/"&gt;WordPress.org&lt;/a&gt;, and thankfully the support email has slowed down ever since the theme was moved from the featured themes. I haven&amp;#8217;t even been spending my free time coding that much. Lack of proper workspace and my dying laptop are what I would blame, but I guess I was kind of tired with all the changes that are happening as&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am rather excited this new stage of life, and I hope I can learn more from my job and the people around&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>When Noise Gets Too Much</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/when-noise-gets-too-much" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-11T23:15:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2013-07-11:blog/when-noise-gets-too-much</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The World Wide Web is an amazing thing. The amount of resources available on it is enormous. You can learn just about anything you can think of with these resources. Recently though, I noticed that amount of low quality content is getting way a lot&amp;nbsp;higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until a few months ago, I collected almost everything I can get my hands on. I bookmarked every programming article I found that looked interesting, even though I barely know anything about the topic. When major tech conferences like Microsoft&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.buildwindows.com"&gt;Build&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/io/‎"&gt;Google I/O&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="http://www.pycon.org"&gt;Pycon&lt;/a&gt; were held, I scanned the videos for titles that looked interesting and downloaded a bunch of them. I saved a bunch of videos from channels like Marakana or Google Tech Talks. I downloaded every single free programming books that people that people on sites like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HN&lt;/span&gt; or reddit, even though I don&amp;#8217;t know what the book talk about that much. As you may have guessed, only a very small portion of those bookmarks ever get visited for the second time, I barely watched any of the videos I downloaded, and most of the ebooks I downloaded never even got extracted from the zip&amp;nbsp;archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until Google announced the plan to shutdown Google Reader, I subscribed to a bunch of tech blogs, blogs like Techcrunch, or Gizmodo. Every morning, I would have 700+ new items on the reader, and I would scanned through all of them, click on what I find interesting, and mark everything else as read. It lasted for several months, but not only it was tedious, I started to realize many of their article are low-quality link-bait, not fact-based articles that fishes for stupid fan-boy arguments. I don&amp;#8217;t want to link to them for examples, but I am sure they aren&amp;#8217;t hard to&amp;nbsp;find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when Google Reader was shut down, I moved to &lt;a href="http://feedly.com"&gt;feedly&lt;/a&gt;, and I took the chance to clean up my feeds. I use &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; only to keep updated with some blogs of people whose writing I find interesting. Most of the are only updated occasionally, and I find myself reading almost every single one of them. The only tech blogs I follow are few that I find still publish actual professional news and pieces I enjoy reading, like &lt;a href="http://theverge.com/"&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt;. I keep up with their updates selectively through channels like Twitter and/ or Facebook instead of trying to keep up with everything they&amp;nbsp;published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same case with the stuffs I kept on my hard drive. I deleted every videos and books that I find not too relevant because of the technology changes, or those that I found not too interesting after I went through them&amp;nbsp;briefly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt great. I feel much more relaxed. During the time I was living with these noises, I felt obligated to read or watch them. Now, not so much. Nowadays, I get my fix from channels such as Twitter, some highly-curated mailing-lists, also the top news on sites like &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HN&lt;/span&gt; and Reddit. I also keep my reading list with Pocket, and keep track of my projects with Trello. It feels good not having to manage them myself (Yes, I know that these cloud services could be shut down any time, but I really hope they won&amp;#8217;t for anytime&amp;nbsp;soon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out, there is a downside to the abundance of information these&amp;nbsp;days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit:&lt;/em&gt; Changed on my opinion on the news&amp;nbsp;site.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>I Bought a Xperia Sola</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/i-bought-a-xperia-sola" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-12T17:40:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2012-07-12:blog/i-bought-a-xperia-sola</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Xperia Sola" src="http://api.sonymobile.com/files/xperia-sola-black-464x515.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few days ago, I bought a new phone, &lt;a href="http://www.sonymobile.com/global-en/products/phones/xperia-sola/"&gt;Sony Xperia Sola&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, its an
Android phone. The Lumia phones are simply fucked up, no upgrade path to
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP8&lt;/span&gt;, and the price that for some reason aren’t going down, I simply
can’t objectively spend my money on it. In addition, without even any
news of when the new Windows Phone 8 are coming out and their price, I
don’t think I can wait. This doesn’t mean that I will stop developing
for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP&lt;/span&gt;, I might buy one for development purpose if they offer a solid
phone at a reasonable price when &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP8&lt;/span&gt; comes out, but then again, without
any news on the new development platform either, it doesn’t mean I will
continue developing for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, enough about &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WP&lt;/span&gt;, lets talk about the new phone instead. The reason
for me choosing this phone is of course, the price-value ratio. It has a
dual-core &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SD&lt;/span&gt; card slot, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFC&lt;/span&gt;, and even a promise of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ICS&lt;/span&gt; upgrade by
Sony. I also considered other options such as &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HTC&lt;/span&gt; One V and Samsung
Galaxy S Advance, but after pondering about all kinds of stuff, I
decided that the Xperia Sola is the best option after all. Now I can
play with Android without dealing with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PITA&lt;/span&gt; emulator that is
included with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SDK&lt;/span&gt;. The screen is pretty bright and clear, and the
loudspeaker are also pretty loud. It also came with 4 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NFC&lt;/span&gt; tags that I
can play&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Android is pretty fun. Most of the essential apps out there are
available for Android, and I can almost do most things that I do on a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt;
with my phone. I installed several reading apps, such as &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aldiko.android&amp;amp;feature=search_result"&gt;Aldiko&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=flipboard.app&amp;amp;feature=search_result"&gt;Flipboard&lt;/a&gt;, and several others. The email client is also pretty
awesome. Other than that, I still need to get used to the on-screen
keyboard, but I think it will be manageable. Although it seems like the
power of Android is also its weak points, in less than a day of using
the phone, I had several apps crash and freezes for no reason, only
cause I can think of is because the many process it is running at once,
which also causes the battery life to be quite&amp;nbsp;short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hendra2392/7554965796/" title="IMG_0007 by p.hdra, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7254/7554965796_574e699c83_b.jpg" width="933" height="622" alt="IMG_0007"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s all for now, I am looking forward to discovering more of
this&amp;nbsp;phone.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="android"></category><category term="phone"></category><category term="xperia sola"></category></entry><entry><title>End of Internship</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/end-of-internship" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-07T16:35:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2012-07-07:blog/end-of-internship</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the last day of my internship at Terato Tech, 20 weeks has
passed by so quickly. I had a lot of fun, learned a lot of new stuffs,
and last but not least, met a lot of interesting&amp;nbsp;people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to leave the project I was working on, and that is a little bit
sad, but I hope I can at least tie up some of the loose ends before I
stop working on it to move on the next project. There are many things
that I wished I had done better, I wish that I actually write a proper
framework for  the game instead of just writing a bunch of messy codes,
but I hope the code that I wrote won’t cause too much&amp;nbsp;trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, well, all in all, I enjoyed my internship very much, and I am very
grateful for the company for having me. Thank you&amp;nbsp;Terato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hendra2392/7559541998/" title="IMG_20120705_230845 by p.hdra, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8294/7559541998_b7f235f911_b.jpg" width="1024" height="768" alt="IMG_20120705_230845"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would have to go back to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UTM&lt;/span&gt; to wait for my visa to be ready before I
go back, so well, we’ll&amp;nbsp;see.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="internship"></category></entry><entry><title>Blocking Time Sucking Sites</title><link href="http://hndr.me/blog/blocking-time-sucking-sites" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-26T23:25:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hendra</name></author><id>tag:hndr.me,2012-06-26:blog/blocking-time-sucking-sites</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is just one thing that I do, and it involves some editing on a
system file, so do it on your own risk. Alright, so one thing that I do to avoid wasting too much time on a
&lt;a href="http://www.9gag.com"&gt;just-for-fun&lt;/a&gt; site, is to completely block it on my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;. Of course, I
can still easily unblock it, but since I am very lazy, most of the time
I simply won’t bother doing&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, the way I do this is by editing the host file on my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;, and point
the domain name of the website that I wanted to stop visiting to the
localhost, which unless I am running a web server at the time, will
simply point to&amp;nbsp;nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows, the hosts file is located at
&lt;code&gt;C:\Windows\System32\drivers\etc\hosts&lt;/code&gt;. Open up that file, and you should
see some description of the file, and an example of the host entry for
the localhost, which points to 127.0.0.1. The format for the host file
is like&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Destination&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;route&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;that&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;you&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;want&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;toroute&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, for example, in my hosts file, I have this&amp;nbsp;line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;www&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;.9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, whenever I enter &lt;code&gt;www.9gag.com&lt;/code&gt;
to my browser, I would get routed to my localhost. Simple&amp;nbsp;enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Linux, the steps are the same, the hosts file is located at
&lt;code&gt;/etc/hosts&lt;/code&gt;. The format are the same as it is on&amp;nbsp;Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that to edit these files, you need to have administrator or root
access on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;OS&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want to edit individual hosts file on every computer you
own, an alternative is to use a service such as &lt;code&gt;OpenDNS&lt;/code&gt;_. You can
register for an account, customize the filtering, and simply configure
the internet access on your computer to use the service. That’s all for&amp;nbsp;now.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hosts"></category></entry></feed>